all right welcome to fix the world
Fridays which I might need to change the
work the name of but I like it I like
the rock Fridays it gets the point
across so I am joined today by Bentley
who's gonna ask some questions on
together Tech and idea cafe well I have
yet to talk to Bentley besides the first
little bit so this will be fresh
off-the-cuff questions that I haven't
prepared for which are my favorite
so together Tech is the idea that a
global tech cooperative is capable of
giving us the tools to basically fix
everything
hence the fix the world Friday that we
can live sovereign individual lives have
amazing diversity' nama skis and have a
meta global efficient community that
that facilitates all of that with the
tools that we own the other in
technology our first project is my other
youtube channel called idea cafe where
we've been having conversations in half
an hour time slots where each
participant takes five minutes to answer
the question that we've generated
together and then we have a brief
conversation after the idea is that it
comes off of youtube where it's very
public and not very many people are
going to want to participate in that
format to become its own platform where
anyone can come on and discuss a topic
that is interesting to them everyone
who's been on there a lot of people are
like I'm nariah I was nervous before
this happened but they've enjoyed the
process because it's not a debate you
don't get it wrong it's just coming
sharing your story hearing other people
share their story and connecting over a
very specific question that you have in
common
so welcome Bentley all right thanks for
having me Jubilee yeah so I just
mentioned on just so everyone kind of
knows I mentioned on YouTube I'd I had a
couple questions and you invited me on
and appreciate that hopefully we'll make
good use of the time what I did want to
try so you gave a little kind of blurb
thereof together tech what I'd like to
do is kind of phrase it back to you to
see whether I'm grokking the project
so it sound good yeah so based on that
and some other things that I've seen
I've watched your little explainer video
you did with the with the whiteboard
sort of software so the way I would kind
of describe it back is kind of like I
said I would see it as kind of like a
nonprofit cooperative where there would
be like you'd suggested about $10 a
month for members and that would give
them access to the apps that are
primarily designed for your muted and I
can unmute you there we go good old
technology stream urine doesn't want
it's discussing how to bring down tech
capitalism all right
maybe cuz I flipped over to another tab
to read my notes but yeah so I don't
know where I ended up meeting there okay
but you know in general that there'd be
a you know maybe something like $10 a
month for the members that get access to
apps that were designed for and designed
and created by the community for the
community for a non-profit you know the
the goal isn't profit the goal is kind
of a game be experiment and that idea
Cafe was kind of one of your first
proposed okay I told you I was gonna be
business you can wait I'm not you're not
telling you right now okay what use
jelly for coal you got like twenty fun
oh great okay that was not necessary for
right now that was but I'll talk to you
about it later
kakie close my door it's a PD day so
normally she's not home on Fridays but
today she is my famous 27 he doesn't
interrupt as often nowadays
final welcome of that habit but yeah so
I don't know if there's that kind of
sound like a like I have a decent
understanding of so far which you have
for for together tack yeah I think so
it's a tech cooperative we own together
run together hopefully as democratically
and transparently as possible but that
can only be within alignment with the
technology we currently have and we fix
it as we go we figure out what's broken
as things break and fix it both the
technology itself which I have no idea
how to do but also just the interactions
and what projects work how the process
of creating it together works how
running it together works we keep on
looking for ways to make it better
yeah I think that's a great idea I've
when I heard of game B which was pretty
recent and I've been working on other I
guess I could say similar ideas some
friends of mine were working on
exponential life satisfaction just so
figuring out ways that we as a group and
could gather people together that would
be able to figure out ways to improve
our life and game B really seems like a
way to do that I did have a question on
when you think about together tech I was
curious to know what skills are you
bringing to this because like you said
you can't develop the tech which is fine
we're gonna need lots of people that
aren't you know developers but where do
you you've went near it again
well yeah where do we what do you see
what what contributions are you willing
and able to put towards this B so that
is a weird question for me to answer
only because I don't fit into any of the
boxes that normally this is one of the
reasons you're like well why don't you
get involved with holo chain like well I
don't know code I'm not a tech person in
fact tech makes you want to throw my
computer through the window quite often
I'm not but I think those are the very
people we need create
Tec there was someone I think it was
extinction rebellion who wanted everyone
to jump on this cord to discuss how we
how we create Tec for its nation
rebellion I was like I hate discord
they're like it's easy like if you're
telling me it's easy you're not
listening it's like so therefore you
need people at a certain level of tech
to even discuss what we could create
together unless issues literally create
ech
what I bring to the table is me as does
everybody my brain my experience seems
to really like creating ideas for
technology that help improve the world
and help create game B that is basically
what my brain has done by itself before
ever encountering game B is the reason
I'm online on YouTube on periscope on
Twitter is in my bedroom by myself I was
like I know how to dismantle capitalism
with my whole pessimistic backgrounds
and everything I had learned up till
that point I was like this is it like
this is what could actually work and so
there is no skill set right like there
isn't there's no degree that says that
there's no like I do have a degree it's
in science but it's a micro amount of
what I know like what my experience is
because I've lived my life I've had I've
had brain tumors in a single mom and
like we're all a microcosm of all of the
talents and challenges that we
experience in life and that is what the
world needs is a way to tap into each
person like what what makes you happy
because the happier you are the more you
have to give the world even if it's
never that you're giving in the
technology company itself your release
like what you're here to give humanity
might be art it might be being an
amazing parent or uncle or that you
never really know someone's contribution
right you can't monetize it you can't
put I know that my contribution what I'm
capable of doing is having a
conversation and attending a meeting and
that's basically all I can do with my
health challenges so unless there's
something easy for me to do like if we
all take on tasks in someone's coding
something I'm never gonna be able to
take that piece on but I don't think
that's kind of what the board of
directors does anyway if there is
important directors that
this is what I can do I can be part of a
conversation and answer questions and I
don't know what that looks like in the
bigger meta project except that I do
like if there was a lot a big piece of
my ego that was like how do I create a
technology company cuz exactly that
question they're gonna kick me out I
don't have anything to offer a
technology company and I don't care even
if I did get kicked out I'm like if I
started it I'm okay with that but bigger
than that any project like this that
doesn't have me on board is hurting
because my brain creates solutions can
think of problems and create solutions
for the meta in a way it can't do for my
interpersonal life like I can create the
idea of a food out how we all eat better
but can't figure out how to like make a
recipe for my family because of the
executive dysfunctioning skills so I
can't figure out how to buy a car my car
broke down I was literally in bed
because when I go under stress my
nervous system shuts down for days but
while I was there I was like figuring
out the entire transportation system for
the world like it's like a weird process
that my brain goes through and so I'm
just going with it and enjoying being
the one behind that it's like that
windshield so yeah what I'm what I'm
hearing is that is that some of the
things you can contributor are like
vision and you know problem-solving and
you know a perspective right on lot of
these tools that would be done which the
the perspective and like would be
something that would I don't know if
we'd say is expected from every member
but would be optional which we can all
kind of provide our perspectives but a
good diversity of perspective would be
important and then I don't know if you
would consider yourself because what
you've been doing with with YouTube and
stuff is that you have been kind of
promoting and a little bit of community
building but I don't know if that sounds
too rigid or you know something that you
wouldn't that you're just doing out of
necessity or if that's something you
enjoy both it start
necessity just like being on social
media started out of necessity but I am
thoroughly enjoying it now good yeah I
mean so that's some of the things that
that I think that you bring to this
process that would be very beneficial
and I just wonder I was just curious
whether that was something how how
painful is that because for some people
they want to see something exist in the
world and for me a lot of the community
building parts is very challenging and
I'd much rather just be sitting writing
code because I'm one of the tech guys
but you can write code all day and if
you know if no one uses it it's a waste
of time yeah and that's basically I mean
I don't know how to write code I've
tried to learn and it does not work for
my brain because it's a language but I
have nuts basically what I've done is
sat and coded a way to dispense
capitalism but it doesn't work unless I
can get other people on board and
explain it and so I basically sat in my
room and decoded how did the immense
amount of capitalism and now I let it go
in the spring to a big degree I was like
oh like I can't sell this if I can't
communicate it so I have to like let go
of my vision recreate it with people and
after encountering game B that is again
the realization I came to is that
although I have something amazing to
offer also I get to let it go and
recreate it with other people because if
it's it's like what you said if you code
you no one's using it it's not it's like
I coded it but it's not useful unless
there's an actual program to run it
unless there's people who want to come
and can see the vision of what
technology gives us and want to
co-create a technological cooperative
yeah yeah so and I have a couple like
small projects that I think could
contribute but I've listening to you
talk I was thinking I really need to
consider I have to be willing to throw
much of it away and restart so that
there's buy-ins important but also that
people can express what their needs are
clearly so we can make sure the
technologies is fulfilling those needs
rather than what I thought those needs
were sitting in my office alone
so yeah so that's something that I've
been thinking about so as far as like
together tech right now what you have is
is you're talking about it on this
YouTube channel on your in your doing
some experiments with idea cafe is there
any other have you written up any other
documents or a website or anything yet
there is a website it's accessible
through my Twitter account it's on the
profile it's a Wix website there's
currently somebody turning it into a
wordpress so it will be together tech
org and it'll be basically what the Wix
website it was which is a basic rundown
of what a tech cooperative can do and
then my blog posting for for a few
months of I forced myself to do a blog
post every week because that was my
deadline I have to try to have something
I'm doing on this project or like like
there was the blog post a week and then
it was YouTube videos daily and now it's
playing game B and just being me and
having fun but showcasing that process
because I get that that is almost as
integral as the idea of the tech company
itself is the person I've had to become
to put it out in the world is like a
course and Happiness is a course in like
authentic but also I don't know how to
communicate it so it's more about
showcasing the process showcasing what
I'm doing as I'm doing it so that
someone else could maybe backtrack and
see see what it looks like yeah yeah I
think that's very brave and has a lot of
value so thanks for doing that so so you
have
uh-oh you went mute again there's a way
I could just like unmute you oh sorry I
mean I made a G that was yeah I'll have
to figure that but yes so the so you
have someone so what level of interest
have you gotten so far I've seen you've
done a couple of kind of videos like
this with two other people I think and
then you said you have someone helping
you out with your website could you have
a feeling for what the level of interest
is so far our participation maybe then
interest well there's a few issues of
course one of witches or spin people who
are like yeah what do i do how do I get
on board I'm like I don't know because I
can deal with one person but once
there's a third person I don't know how
to actually um I don't know how to
actually create like um deal with the
third person I'm like okay well we set
up a time period now I don't know how to
like I can what's the word like
negotiate talk through something with
one person but two people and like I
don't know I'm figuring out how to do
this process I've been following which
is following my own internal guidance
and how to do that with somebody else
who's also doing that and and how do we
then when our visions separate right how
do we how do we figure that out and
that's part of me going back to that to
the drawing board I think I forgot the
question which was uh I was just saying
about how many people you kind of have
either already doing something or I'm
just trying to get a feel for where
where the idea is that right now is hard
so participation from other people so
far comment to you in there to comment
to you on something that's not not
useful so I believe and this is my
hypothesis is if what we I'm creating
what we are creating was presented in a
way that wasn't me in my bedroom with
black in the backgrounds like was an
actual video that was edited and
explained it professionally there would
be a ton of people who wanted to get
involved but I don't know what that
looks like so I don't even want to
pursue that because I'm like unless
there's someone else you on board if you
know what that looks like
right now within my capacity what I'm
looking for is basically having a board
of directors median with
other people on camera and talking about
what is the step to actually start
something right what is that and so it
has to people who are willing to go
through the process on camera because
that is how we transparently show how
we're creating a global tech cooperative
so that anyone can come on board and
start becoming a member and my vision
what I hypothesize is that if it gets
like if there's four three of us having
a conversation and hundreds of people
watching if we need anything done
there'll be enough people who are like
especially if it's a little thing that
needs to get done right there'll be
someone with that skill set someone who
wants to do it and the third thing is to
get a task done wants to do it oh is
aware they're aware because I watching
it so things will get there rather
easily
I just keep finding the next iteration
that's like okay that's something I can
do within my capacity and what I can do
is show up to a meeting and therefore if
we're able to have meetings online on a
video it can move forward with me to
meanness and everyone doing working
within their capacity doing what is fun
and easy for the individual but
collectively we move it forward even
though collectively right now is just me
myself yeah so far yeah so you would so
it seems like you're thinking that the
next step would be to get some people to
I mean there's you do you think the next
step is to go of to people like you
right now it's you and me but to go to
three and then do you me it sounds like
you need help with scheduling that and I
don't know if you want a format for that
or if you already have a form I don't
particularly have a format for it as far
as just getting together and having like
you know what was what did we say we
were gonna do last week to move it
forward
and what needs to get done if if what
needs to get done is not something
anyone wants to take on or can take on
that it kind of needs to be put on the
shelf until there is somebody who can
take that on right like we need to look
at the legality of something and we
don't have a lawyer and we can't fund a
lawyer if we don't have funding then you
know like okay well that's something
that needs to get done I don't even know
what's I know there's software out there
to do that way if they all call
moaning and they all or I don't know
about them but other people know how to
use like Google Docs and do things that
facilitate that and that's not quite my
strong point but I know there are people
out there who can who will know how to
do it I just know the more brains are in
the room the more people are in the room
the more that solutions can be found
especially if you're looking for them
but you're not looking to have a debate
you're looking for like how do we
problem solve this and we'll probably
have conflict and have to deal with that
as well and that's part of showcasing
what it is I mean entrepreneurs don't do
this on camera right they do it behind
closed doors and then present a polished
package I don't think that's what we do
I think we showcase the problem so that
all the members can see because they're
just as integral to the process so if
the board of directors can't figure out
how to fund it if the Board of Directors
run short of money they're not really
the board of directors like a normal
company the rest of the people can't
really yell at them because right we
showed you the financials you could have
also said that we should have spent
money here we spent too few here could
have gotten more members right so the
idea is just that the Board of Directors
if a smaller group has to be empowered
than we're empowering a smaller group
right now we're starting with me and if
you want to join you know a B and then
we would find a time and facilitate we
wouldn't necessarily need suit on camera
but co-create what the on camera meeting
looks like right every week and and then
meet at that time until a third person
wants to join and if they wanted to join
but they couldn't meet that time then we
might be able to facilitate a time
between the three of us but once a
fourth person comes on board were not
changing the time right it's gonna be
the same hour every week because when
you get to ten people one of the chances
you're able to find I don't know if you
were in game B when I tried the idea
cafe experiment with the like six hour I
came in just after it and I did I I
experienced the issue that you
eventually found out is that you know if
you leave it on all the time no one's
there at the same time so yeah so I just
missed that
yeah you mean the cafe in general
because there was the county they
started it was 24 hours and it was
amazing but then yeah you'd start just
it's served to Peter off because you get
in and you'd have to wait a long time
for someone else to pop in so you
weren't having the conversations so I
came up with this idea that I kind of
came up before the extinction rebellion
I was like if there's enough people and
you have a way to facilitate it or you
all don't have to be at the same
conversation then you can have a
conversation every four hours so there's
six different time slots within a 24
hour period and like the question
changes every day or every two days and
which is what the idea Cafe is based
around the World Cafe which is an
in-person way of having a conversation
they don't take five minutes to talk
each necessarily but you that's not true
they'd sure they have the 20 minute time
slot to have a conversation with four
people and then they switch tables and
they have it with a new four people and
a new four people and so it's kind of
trying to do that with game B but there
weren't enough people to facilitate it
so the idea is not just that you come to
one conversation but you come to
multiple conversations so there's a
bigger conversation going on and that
didn't happen because there's only you
know a few hundred people in the game B
space and only a handful of that
participating in them in the Xoom
conversation but it's possible if we got
big enough to be able to facilitate
something like that where everyone can
be part of the conversation it wants to
be
yeah and and really I guess when you
have you know two to four people you
just it's just one session and you don't
move around because you don't have
enough people but that there's still
value in that right I here's what I
would like how I would like to
participate I I don't have a lot of time
a lot of family things and stuff like
that but I think I can carve out you
know an hour a week to talk to this and
as long as you think that I'm providing
value I would like to to do that so how
do you think about that
I mean it I think we 100% on board for
that I think with anyone that comes on
board I mean if actually game B I know
that we have a lot of alignments and
values of what we want to create in this
world I also think that like let's say
we do this for a few weeks and we have
like a posey-like we just we can't work
together great then we don't work to get
or Namie like them we don't work
together or we figure out that conflict
it makes us stronger like it's just
figuring it out as we go it's part of
the process and yeah I'm a board for
that okay so maybe we could just if this
times already set aside in you're okay
using that time for that then I can put
it permanently on my schedule and we
could see how it goes yeah sounds good
and how long do you normally do these
for you do for about an hour or 30
minutes I have been doing them for 30
minutes just because there haven't been
people asking questions so I just come
on in
diatribe for half an hour okay this is
what there's also a possibility crowd
democracy this YouTube video or this has
been around for a couple years I have
like hundreds of videos and I have 60
subscribers like it's not a big a big
YouTube channel just like the idea Cafe
became its own YouTube channel creating
one that is together tech that is like
the our board meetings right like it's
like here's where we're starting and
we're doing it at 11 a.m. on Fridays if
I wanted to move this to a different
time period of like QA for the bigger
tech cooperative that I like you know
doing just answering people's questions
on how we create a better world and my
brain likes to answer questions did that
make sense that we I'm okay doing it
here in fact I'd say we should probably
start doing it here until there's more
people on board and then yeah make sure
it works and we have some momentum going
and then figure out
yeah I've I'm often the person that I
have an idea and I built a whole website
and then of course I you know I don't do
anything with it
so I'm learning to do smaller iterations
and proof points yeah there's two
projects because the idea cafe the idea
behind the idea cafe is we need a way to
have a conversation
a lot of humanity so that we can
understand what they need and understand
where they are and also just connect
people I think that just having a way to
really connect on social media solves a
lot of our problems of like yelling
across each other over akhrot chambers
and trolling and I've yet to kind of
meet someone who's on camera who's
willing to be an ass yeah like you know
our personalities might conflict but
it's not the same people still want to
watch what they say but it's it's it's a
whole other level that I think that
for-profit social media is never going
to tap into because that's not where the
money is or I there could be money there
but they that's not what they started
doing so they like conflict pays right
putting a personification of your life
on Instagram that isn't real pays them
in a way that being real and authentic
doesn't right but there are other
projects that aren't the idea cafe
mainly the labor platform which gives us
a lot of money to deal with everything
else so maybe we don't even need to
charge $10 a month and it helps
dismantle the minimum wage and do a lot
of it does a lot creating a labor
platform it's like uber and TaskRabbit
and all the things that people are
already doing in a way for a for-profit
company right the sharing economy that
isn't really the sharing economy in a
for-profit company something like that
that is cooperative where all of them
everyone who is an employee is part of
the cooperative and so are the people
who are hiring them and figure out how
to get health insurance figured that's a
big project though also like that's not
a simple one the third one that I was
just kind of coming up with last week
which might be something that would more
appeal to you based on what you just
said about building websites that then
don't go anywhere is a Yelp for websites
there are so many projects out there
that are amazing but they go away
because nobody there isn't the threshold
of people so what I would love to do is
find this kind of what I was working in
the last few days is possibly just
interviewing people on here is getting
some of those people who have projects
either on the go or have had projects in
the past whether they've been successful
or a failure a learning projects
something they learned from yeah and
saying like what was the biggest
obstacle I believe it's that people
weren't there right they didn't have the
funding right I didn't have and so
creating
a Yelp for websites one that we the user
trusts like if we can build trust into
it because we're creating it together
it's a cooperative we're putting very
transparently what that process is to
say whether a project is good or bad and
also having it be because it's a
cooperative the people can keep adding
features to it right like I care about
the accessibility of an app game B might
care about how game B the app is right
is this a game be app or is this a game
a up even if it's owned privately the
idea isn't that these are just our
cooperative ones
it's that anyone who has one Google
anyone but mainly the little mom-and-pop
ones who start something and it's
amazing but nobody comes on board so it
goes away having it be in a way if it's
good we're gonna get you people right
like if it's something that you create
that my brother's crazy and that
Wikipedia for politicians right now
which I know a ton of people would want
but he doesn't know how to market it
enough to get people on board it's like
right that's the problem with every
single technology and app that comes out
is that people who create them aren't
necessarily great at marketing it
doesn't mean the thing is it good or
they it's great and they can get people
on board but they charge $10 a month and
people don't want to pay $10 a month
right if you can have a conversation
with your customers like hey we have a
hundred thousand people if you have that
many customers could you maybe charge
two dollars a month right like what is
the that like working with the people
creating the tech that own the tech
themselves and the people using it and
creating a system of how do we know we
can trust it because that's the problem
I trust my brother but you why would you
trust my brother right if he's in kind
it you don't know him so that and they
even like if we create this they'd have
to trust us to do it but if it's
transparent and cooperatively owned that
trust is like kind of dissipate it out
to the projects right we're like you
don't need to go through Google or the
App Store and have a five star rating in
order to get people on board we just
need to get people on board to this one
project and then they're able to be able
any project that is going to benefit you
you're able to hear about right if
there's a food app one and we can
compare the ones that have saturated
markets right like food apps and
financial apps what features and
benefits do they have and which one's
the best
basically all of those have one blog
post out there saying that but who are
you
who wrote the blog post was it a paid
blog post how do I know and then they
click on them at six months a year later
and half of them are out of business and
so I think that is a fairly easy
application it like as far as to cut
like the technology per unit creating a
new Yelp isn't rocket science mr.
vibrating but it's not it's getting
people who already have tech projects on
board getting enough of them on board
that they want to have just to say right
and like oh yeah this is how this would
have helped me in my project right
having these features and benefits and
then a ton of people who use apps ie
everybody saying what do you care about
what do you trust what don't you trust
I'm doing great something like that so
and that also sounds like kind of a good
initial iteration of together tech
because it's also marketing tools could
pry the wrong term but you know a way to
to get it out there to get some sharing
and for people to be aware of it and
then those other apps so yeah that's
that's an interesting idea
ya know it starts because it's also it
shows us holes in the marketplace to
create our next ones it helps us find it
the ones that like one at you if you've
watched the Netflix of apps that we can
license them right the runs that are
like yeah if you bring me a hundred
thousand people I can license it for a
dollar per month and if there's enough
of those that can work together right
having it so that we're we're helping
them that's Omni win it's transparent
and it's not you know like we're gonna
help you milk our customers for all
they're worth because the point isn't
the point is the opposite of that is
like how do we get the individual human
projects that are gonna help improve
their lives beyond marketing right mark
me it's kind of like a lion to you to
convince you were the best this is like
are you actually the best will you put
your money where your mouth is because
my guess is the apps are gonna have to
pay for the process of getting rated
properly and that's where the money
comes from but it's transparent so it's
like $1000 to get your operate it I
don't know we would discuss all the
funding sources but if that's the case
it isn't you give us a thousand dollars
we give you a five star rating it's you
go through the process of us rating and
if you're a for-profit company and we're
tell
people what it is right so we have
enough people going through the process
and rating it and saying what works and
doesn't work and in a way that you can
then even make it better right that's
the beauty of apps they're not movies
they're not released and then they are
what they are they can be made evolve
yeah yeah the most of the app developers
I know several of it well most of them
are nonprofits mm-hmm so we'll have to
figure that which is huge I mean those
people being part of the iteration for
talking about how we get people and born
to them that's amazing right because
we've got those are the exact ones we
want to succeed they might not be the
ones to pay a thousand dollars to get it
to get it right in right and so there
can absolutely be different funding
sources for like you're a for-profit app
it's charging $10 a month we want to
know if you're worth $10 a month versus
a not-for-profit here's how you recycle
your stuff that is never making money
anyway we want to get people to you how
do we facilitate that for you right that
is beyond necessarily wanting to make
money off of them yeah yeah my gut is I
or at least I don't see yet how the
model there's a lot of challenges with
the model of charging a thousand a month
but I don't have enough money right
number one time review well yeah yeah
and I'm not saying it I know that it
won't work
but they I don't envision how that works
but I don't have any other funding
practices in mind that would work so
that would be the one to pursue I don't
know what they are but enough people if
there's five of us I guarantee we can
come under the weighted transparent
about that like listen we have to go
through a period of having advertising
until we get to its end dollar a month
fee the words worth it we need to do
this this portion of it and but I agree
that I first of all more nobody we don't
have the trust and we don't have the
people starting $1,000 a month
breaks us before we start but if we have
a million people and we're like listen
a million customers potentially oru
that's when it starts being worth money
to them to be like okay if we get
assessed this is what we're getting for
it right we get instant marketing it's
real marketing it's like these people
want to be on board we're solving a
problem for them and they want to be
here and because we've created into it
like the longevity of an app I feel like
it hurts everyone like when the fact
that what I just said you go to a blog
post and nine out of ten of them are
gone you're like okay well if I'm buying
a lifetime subscription what does that
mean if you're gonna be gone in three
months if I'm giving you my children's
picture so you can make photo albums or
something but I want to have access to
them in ten years I can't trust you to
be here in ten years and the more apps
come in and go out of business that fast
the worse the next one has it and the
next one has it and the more we can kind
of build longevity into the model for
everybody if it's a good product I think
that that helps them and also us the
user yeah a lot of businesses because
they were venture funded they eventually
had to shut down not that they weren't
profitable they just weren't
exponentially profitable so yes so
pulling that requirement out would
increase the longevity of those apps
quite a bit especially so I was I was
thinking of also wondering whether there
might be people that would be willing to
quote donate ten dollars a month to see
this in existence and go ahead and start
the tech together tech as the you know
and then with that ten dollars a month
we're having we're keeping the server's
up and maybe giving a few people you
know some nominal pays it's no wouldn't
be enough to be considered pay but yeah
yeah to do reviews and to do that and
stuff like that and and tell me get
enough funding towards self-supportive I
think with apps in particular
mhm payments especially if you're
someone like me who doesn't use tech
right I'm not gonna know the code I'm
not gonna know that piece the payment is
the free app and I think about a YouTube
star who gets all this stuff given to
them and then they're a sponsor for it
it's like the payments is you get to try
this you get to try all ten of these
food apps right you get to try these two
food apps you gets it like that you
potentially get to have whether we have
to pay for in the beginning because
they're not going to know us to jump on
board or if we've approached the food
apps and say hey we need you to give us
100 subscriptions to each of yours so we
can rate you so we can say how good you
are if you believe in your product you
will and if you don't great let's put on
our website that you wouldn't give us a
hundred and you know oh that's fine we
started here with one and we looked at
features and benefits and we didn't you
know we had one personally builder there
are other things that can be perks that
aren't necessarily paying them for their
mm-hmm further reading like Yelp doesn't
pay people to go to restaurants right
they choose to go to the the restaurants
they pay for it and then they they rate
it based on based on that but I do think
there could be people who want to pay
$10 a month for together tech because of
the vision and those people are game B
people right even if they don't know
what game B is there are people who want
a better world they can see how tech
gets us there that we owned together
they're not getting a catalogue of apps
for their $10 a month they're getting to
know they were in from the ground floor
right they're getting to co-create
together tech like that's the point
right it's like right if you enjoy that
process getting to watch the videos
getting to be getting to participate
being on the zoom conversations and
getting your say in it and putting
putting that piece in it I just don't
necessarily I don't know how to get
enough people on board to make that
feasible right we don't need ten people
paying $10 a month we need like a
thousand people paying $10 but yeah and
I was wondering though if it's worth the
while to even though it wouldn't be
enough money to do anything just to
start it off correct or start off with
that process of go ahead start
collecting the funds but then we'd also
have to decide what tech to use for that
like you could use patreon some people
concerned about patreon you could use
PayPal
which not real happy with paypal at the
moment just to kind of kind of get the
get the ball rolling and the culture of
kind of donating to this process
of course they would be getting a value
back but would the value
I just kind of used the term kind of
donation or because it's you know the
values not quite commiserate for ten
dollars a month maybe I agree and maybe
it doesn't start at ten dollars a month
maybe in the beginning we start and sure
enough but honestly ten dollars a month
because they aren't really getting
anything for it
ten dollars a month isn't a lot for most
people it is enough for their life it's
basically like you're donating it right
it's like tapping into people's
altruistic nature not their financials
like that this is gonna pay off because
it's never gonna pay off as far as
you're not going to get dividends you're
gonna go that's not true you're gonna
get big dividends but like game B
dividends right like anything that you
put in that we get back everybody gets
back it's not because you were in at the
ground floor like you get access to all
of the tech we create but you get to say
you were in from the beginning you get
to say you were in from this period of
time and I think there are people in
game B who have money and believe in it
enough that they would put in and that's
where it might be understandable to have
like $1 a month to say I care about this
but that's what I can afford because if
this wasn't my project that would be how
much I would put into it like I'd be
like without a month to put this forward
yeah this it's my project even though
I'm I'm like a single mom on disability
I would put $10 a month in to say yes I
believe in this this is like how we
create game B but there can also be
people who possibly go upwards of you
know 50 $100 a month if it's not if
they're really if there's someone who
has the funds to be able to do that and
they believe in this right to be able to
say the issue is you don't get more of a
stay in it for that amount so it's just
you gets more altruistic points right
more like I saw the vision of this back
in the day and I gave yeah so gave me
some recognition that would be a good
perk yeah so one of my similar ideas to
the one you mentioned about
what was it so having a website review
that reminds me of another thing where I
was think about that one of the
potential first apps might also be like
I don't know what else to call it but
kind of a self-help app so I've been
thinking of some ways to have people be
able to kind of enter where they're at
like mentally financially physically and
all this stuff and it would help them
craft a plan and would then guide them
to other resources because we don't need
to reinvent anything if there's a great
video on how to do push-ups correctly
then we would link to that but there's
we're in the information age and we're
overloaded with information just having
a process that would kind of sort
through all that information and give
you some guidance I think would be very
helpful and could be call so kind of
crowd-sourced information and so that
kind of that just when you talked about
website review it reminded me that
that's that's kind of similar I mean
this would be more of a review of
everything that could that you could
potentially use like reading almost like
goal-setting groups right like we want
to run a marathon and you create a group
and you can I don't know why you'd be
zooming them if you're running a
marathon that maybe you can't find
writing partners your spacing or just an
accountability group right well also
having the resources I'm creating
because that's the connection piece is
missing in so many people's lives if we
give them that connection if we give
them a way to be able to jump on and
find people without having to bring them
so social media doesn't do is it doesn't
assign you friends okay
you have to bring your own and some
people don't have them some people don't
have the safety around them that has
that so I don't know if that appeals to
you but like with her it's like hey if
you want to work out here are people to
kind of do that with or yeah
I think that's great idea it's it's not
something I would have thought of but I
think that's great and I definitely
could see that as being part of it and
that I don't know if that fits under
kind the idea cafe or if it's I guess
it's really kind of a separate thing
well how do you think about that well
with the idea cafe the first iteration
in my head was like we have once it's
created and it's its own platform we
start out with one question a day and
everybody answers that same question and
then I found it hard to get people kind
of on board to have my 11:00 a.m. on
Wednesday conversation when I would
create the question so then I changed it
that I found I'm finding one person we
co-create a question together that we
want to answer and then we put set a
time and the worst that happens is
there's two of us right which is great
it's actually great conversations so
then it changed it in my head I was like
okay this thing isn't necessarily for
building together tech together this
thing is for connection with people so
creating a question and saying here's
your time period and you can if you're
not available during that time period
but you want to answer that question
like there's ways to say yes I would
love to answer any of these questions
and here's my availability we match
people up to have conversations with the
minimum of two and maximum of four
people and in that way it could it's
like it's random degree right you're
just randomly getting assign to three or
four people and that will work for some
people and it'll be amazing and other
people want to talk to the same people
again and again and kind of form an
actual community and so I think there's
ways to do all of that with the with the
platform right we're like it's about the
individual getting what they need and
what they want and the backend
facilitating that so you have a
dashboard of like oh here's the group's
where I'm like talking about parenting
and I want those to be much more
intimate and I want to know those people
here's my game be creation ones that are
like I don't care who I matched up with
anyone yeah we'll talk about anything
that related and other ones that are
like autistic people with their special
interests like I want to talk about
trades all day every day I don't care
who what's around right and or maybe
they do want to have the same people
again and again
and having it be very individually
focused like what's gonna add to your
life
and having that be also goal setting
right that there's that piece of it that
gives you we have a goal to create
together because there's not many brains
in the room right I mean if you have
four people who want to go on a specific
diet they want to start doing keto even
if none of them know anything about keto
together being able to create that and
then especially if there's a way to give
that to the next group who starts it
right be like hey we did the research
and this is what we did this is the
YouTube video that we found and
explained it well and here are the
people that works for ya or there was
yeah yeah in in the idea cafe you do
have towards the question I think at one
point you're suggesting that is also
being part of the decision-making
process for together tech my concern
about that or my thought about that was
how can we make sure that that that that
the learnings accumulate from those
meetings otherwise someone would have to
kind of like sit through a majority the
meetings to be to consume that
conversation and although we'd want them
to participate there there I would I'd
like there to be some way for knowledge
to build I don't know if you thought
through that yet I haven't thought
through it as far as I know it's the
thing that needs to happen but I don't
have B solution for it in the world cafe
it's an in-person option that like a
for-profit or not-for-profit does with
like dozens or hundreds of people and
it's for a set period of time right it's
for four hours that they're answering
questions around tables and they're
drawing on the they're drawing on the
tablecloth like they have paper there
and they take some paper with them and a
and so you kind of collect those and
that's the the piece the online world
cafe does it on a Google Doc for each
table or like 20 people participating go
and kind of like will type in if you
want to go by I was never a table where
we wanted to actually take notes I was
like the point isn't necessarily that
it's continued learning it's that you
change right that you leave a different
person you are you're the one
like you're the one continually going on
so if people are participating one-off
conversations it's still part of the
participatory group who some of those
people will have been at yesterday's and
the day before and the day before and
other people this is their first time
the questions are designed in such a way
but you don't necessarily need to know
that but it would be great to have like
a previously on write like to catch you
up here's where we are
for every maybe they're a week old but
like this is what you get from before
but there that's also where the board of
directors comes in right like where
there's a small group of people or group
of people who are choosing to be more
involved and staying in the process and
they're the ones who like we don't
necessarily need to disseminate that
information because it's there it's that
we are stay connected and we're the ones
generating we might be the ones
generating questions like here's the one
we need them to answer here's the one we
need them to answer and questions that
they're uploading right if there's one
that they're uploading we're like okay
well they want that answer that's
clearly important um yeah awesome so
yeah so idea Cafe is is both a benefit
in itself of just having people talk
people finding community people having
interaction more meaningful than current
social media but also it's a it's a
co-creation process for together tech as
well or can that's one of the potential
uses of idea Cafe right absolutely so I
would yeah I have some tech that we
could also look at for that I know the
founder of Kiko chat Qi qo chat comm he
has it's where you can have a group of
like 50 people and then there's breakout
rooms and in the current iteration I
think you choose which breakout room you
want to go to based on topic which is a
little different although he might have
a random assignment and it has it built
in instead of Google Docs it uses an
open-source version of Google Docs it's
like I'm just gonna say a lot of the
bones are there for similar processes
and so we could see whether that fits
the need or if he would be willing to
augment his system or if we need to
develop you know it's just an option to
look at yeah no that's cool I don't want
to reinvent things that are don't need
to be reinvented so I was like will you
zoom because I know they have breakout
rooms
Jordan was talking about one of my
friends Daniel was also talking about
the idea that the World Cafe is like
you're assigned to people you sit there
and talk for 20 minutes then you leave
there's another type of iteration of
that where you have a central room and
then someone will pick a question and
they'll form a group around that let go
off and talk and then you kind of vote
with your feet where if the quite big
conversation so everyone doing water
someone's been authorized that you go
back to the main group and then there's
enough of you there that's when you then
can form a new group and pick a new
question and I'm wondering if when you'd
actually because that sounded like a
great I was like that sounds good
yeah that's open spaces are open yeah
yeah yeah I've I've been to one of those
wants in real life it was interesting
kyouko chat because it's like if it's
breakout groups you can come back to
yeah so you care yeah each person could
that has the topic can make down rooms
they've no one shows up and no one shows
up people can come it coming out I don't
know the room see I would be like a
virtual form of that which also has
video and it uses zoom in the background
as its video host company yeah yeah so
that's one potential so yeah so as we
kind of get together and talk these
times and with whoever else ends up
joining yeah talking through kind of
each of these ideas and just seeing
where where we want to take it next yeah
because there's Prout there's like
complexity of the thing there is how
much it would cost to make it which
honestly I don't know because I'm not a
tech person I'm just like magic happens
and then it's made right you guys will
have a more of an understanding people
in tech of like how complicated it is to
make and whether you could do it or
whether would have to be you know
someone else doing it anyone Cody and I
feel like has to get paid unless it's
like an afternoon project which aren't
even know if there's anything that's an
afternoon project but yeah that like
there's different funding models there's
like that's where the labor platform is
an instant funding model
funds basically everything else but and
starting with one like cleaners right
like what how do we bring cleaners on
board and and do and do that piece it
doesn't necessarily need to be all labor
all of the time and then we're
constantly looking like how do we make
your life easier
cleaners right and that eventually we
figure out health care right like well
everyone can have health care who's part
of our platform who wouldn't right it's
in the States and Canada maybe less so
but even in Canada our people work
places like Starbucks for extended
health benefits be able to come on board
and be like yeah I work one hour a week
but I can buy into my health care plan
yes it's amazing yeah yeah so probably
start kind of listing these ideas out
and figuring out where we want to what's
the next step for which ones are however
we want to do it yeah sounds good
like brainstorming a little bit more I
get excited about just talking about the
idea itself and then brainstorming like
what a beta of it would look like right
or what mm-hmm
not a beta what the like game the final
product looks like then like and bring
it back to reality
get your big vision yeah yeah and I do
kind of see all of these this kind of
game be experiments on trying to put
game be and in the real world and
iterate which is my my leaning more on
that side rather than the kind of game
be self improvement which I I do myself
but I am also eager to start kind of
playing around with it yeah I I came up
with the idea and then I had to do self
improvement to get there and I think
that a fault of game B is that it seems
to almost require people have a certain
level of interpersonal development in
order to participate which is OK for
game B in those spaces at the same time
I don't think together tech can require
that like you don't need to have a
personal growth requirement to use
Twitter or Facebook right so to be able
to say
we need to meet people where they are
like which is the IDB town the DIA Cafe
is you don't need to be emotionally
intelligent to come and participate in a
conversation and that requires you to
just show up as you are there might be
conflict because of that and we deal
with that and possibly separate people
based on their conflict but those kind
of things like how do we if we do think
we're more personally you know like
we've had our personal growth how can we
use that personal growth to help people
who may never get there they might not
want you that's not what they're here to
do here didn't do their own thing under
Cory not yeah and I think a lot of
people recognize game B's well a lot of
people wanted to happen pretty soon but
we don't even really know what it is yet
right but there there there will be some
transitionary things like I threw a
project idea in there in it I said well
it's just kind of game B because it has
some of the philosophy but it's
competitive so so but people seem to be
of the opinion that it's okay to have
something that's encouraging people
towards game B even if it has a little
bit of game a left in it as a
transitionary tech and so that yeah so
that may be necessary just like you know
we're talking about something using you
know today's monetary standards but in
the future you know and we're using kind
of the standard some of the standard
incentives it's hard to just jump
straight to the ideal game B without
having some steps in between absolutely
I think that's fair I mean we have to
start where we are and I think it's like
a simultaneously talking about the big
picture you proto peon Society of like
we're like looks utopian from where we
are now but in 10 or 15 years you know
you have your own new set of problems to
deal with mm-hmm and also great what is
the beta what is like the thing we do
first what is the like very simple thing
that gets us there and that's where like
right having a social media that
actually connects you having a way to
get information that you trust having a
way to get information on what apps can
help you get information on what you
trust like having it be and it's just
about picking like one project and
starting and both playing it out
with people which is what I'm learning
I'm like okay I get a co-create with
people that's actually what I wanted but
I had to get to a purchased a certain
personal development level to actually
be open to that yeah and now is the time
like a year ago I wouldn't like it was
like people wanted to come on board it
was like don't touch my baby no I'm like
no let's go create a whole new one I
hate like it and there's a certain truth
there but it's like but wait you don't
understand you don't get it cuz I didn't
explain it and now now I can let I
explained it enough to me that I can let
it go and be like oh this is naturally
what we create we naturally create
something that's transparent and
democratic or better especially with me
at the table right I'm not gonna be like
sure we can let's be fascists great as
long as I get a million dollars that's
just not who I am so it's not happier
yeah no that's all right well this was
awesome and fun and so we're gonna do it
again and 11:00 a.m. ex writing yes yep
all right so I'll write out some just to
let you know what I'm gonna do I'm gonna
write out some more ideas and try and
get my thoughts organized and then we
can just chat through it and and then of
course anything that you want to talk
about yeah sounds good I'm gonna show up
if I think of some between now and then
I will do that and otherwise I am just
following my own journey and yeah I
posted on Democracy Now youtube and
periscope and Twitter as things come up
because it is unlike my brain wants to
co-create text so it's just gonna keep
putting it out there but I love that
this is that we're starting something
that is like this our time block and I'd
say we share this in game be and invite
other people or not yet mm-hmm
yeah I I think I think we can I think
they're all pretty experimental so I
hope they'll take it in that in the
spirit in which we're doing it yeah this
this technology can only facilitate six
of us but I mean worst best-case
scenario we can also use zoom I don't
know how to do that and put it on
YouTube
but I'm sure we can yeah I could help
figure that out if we get to that point
yeah